http://www.appaloosa.org.uk/legal-notice

Privacy Policy -
including Terms & ConditionsThe British Appaloosa Society respect the privacy of our members, supporters and visitors to our website. This policy is concerned with how we collect information, what we do with it and what controls you have. We aim to be completely transparent and promise to make sure that we treat personal information and data with the due care and respect it deservesYour PrivacyThe British Appaloosa Society was established in 1976 and as a registered Charity our aim is to preserve, protect and promote the British Appaloosa Horse. We are passionate about Appaloosas and could not operate without the support of our valued membershipWe take our duty to control and process your personal data very seriously. This policy explains how we collect, manage, use and protect your personal data.Your data is safe with us. We take our obligations very seriously and we will never sell your data to third party organisations. We will only contact you via methods we have received your consent for us to use and you can contact our Data Protection Officer any time you wish to change the way we contact you or opt out of future communications but please understand that in opting out you would not receive your regular newsletter or any other correspondence relating to your membership and participation within the Society.We may change this document from time to time to reflect the latest view of what we do with your information. Please check back frequently; you will be able to see if changes have been made by the date it was last updated.Who are we?This policy references to the British Appaloosa Society which is a registered charity in England and Wales 1103432. A non-profit making company limited by guarantee. Registered in England No. 4836875 at 10 Roman Way, Wantage, Oxon OX12 9YFWhat personal data we collect and how we use it?The British Appaloosa Society is what is known as the controller and the processor of the personal data that you provide to us. We will usually collect basic personal data about you such as your name, postal address, telephone number, email address and occasionally, your bank details if you are supporting us financially by joining the Society as a member, sponsoring an event or competition, purchasing promotional merchandise from our shop or paying for an Equine passport service with us. Data can also include image or images either owned by you or taken by us at our shows and events. In the case of Junior or Student members we will also collect your date of birth as we need to verify you are in the correct membership plan. We will be very clear with you that we need to collect such information, our reason for collecting such information, and we would only do so with your permission.Why we need itAs a Passport Issuing Organisation – Our Services:  (Legal Basis) Information collected under a Legal ObligationAs an official Equine Passport Issuing Organisation we are responsible for the lawful production of horse passports, working under the jurisdiction of the Defra Minimum Operating Standards and European Union Directives on Horse Passport production. We are legally required to hold names and addresses of breeders and also current and past owners in order to produce and maintain equine passports lawfully, the information being necessary to fully comply with the law relating to Horse Passports. All this Data is held securely by us and obtained by a Legal Obligation under the General Data Protection Regulations 2018.
The information is never shared with any third party without permission of the current owner unless it becomes a legal requirement to do so, but we are required to supply limited, routine data sharing of some information under written contract with The UK Central Equine Database. You have the right to inspect the information we retain on you in these circumstances but you do not have the right to have the information removed as it is necessarily retained by law.Membership: Information (Legal Basis) Legitimate InterestWe collect your personal data in order to deal with your participation in membership of the Society as a members club.
It enables us to provide you with updates, regular newsletters, enables you to make product purchases, give feedback, make donations, to participate in competitions and interact on our social media forums, on our website and also to enable you to engage with, and participate in, horse shows and social events that we provide for our members.
This may include the use of your name and/or image(s) being reproduced in show results, in show programmes and catalogues, within the regular Members Newsletter and on the Society website. We may use your data on our breed event promotional display boards, on social media or in magazine or newspaper press releases purely to promote the British Appaloosa Society, its members and the appaloosa breed.The information we collect is either needed to fulfil your request or to enable us to provide you with a more personalised service. You don't have to disclose any of this information to browse our website. However, if you choose to withhold requested information, we may not be able to provide you with certain services.Processing your Information:
By Legitimate InterestWe have a number of lawful reasons that mean we can use (or 'process') your personal information. One lawful reason is something called 'legitimate interests'. Broadly speaking Legitimate Interests means we can process your personal information if:•	We have a genuine and legitimate reason and we are not harming any of your rights and interests.Sometimes, with your consent, we will process your personal data to provide you with information about our activities that you have requested or are expecting. We may process personal data when we need to do this to fulfil a contract (for example, if you have purchased something from our merchandise shop and need Royal Mail or other Courier to deliver an order to you) or where we are required to do this by law. We may processes your data when it is in our legitimate interests to do this and when these interests do not override your rights. Those legitimate interests include providing you with information on our appeals, products, fundraising, newsletter interaction, feedback, competitions and other activities such as open days, social and equestrian events. When we process your personal information for our legitimate interests, we will consider and balance any potential impact on you and your rights under data protection and any other relevant law. Our legitimate business interests do not automatically override your interests – we will not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law).How we obtain your details?We collect your personal information in a number of ways:•	When you provide it to us directly.•	When you provide permission to other organisations to share it with us (including Facebook, Twitter).•	When we collect it from you via our website contact forms or by you freely contacting us with a question or request•	When you have given it to a third party and you have provided permission to pass your information on to us.If you do not wish your data to be used in any of the ways listed above or have questions about this then please contact our Data protection Officer (details below)ChildrenIf you are under 16 please ensure you obtain your parent/guardian's written consent before sending any personal information to any website including The British Appaloosa Society. We do have activities for our junior members so we may ask your age. Before taking part please ensure you speak to your parent or guardian for their permissionPlease note that we will not knowingly market to or accept donations or orders for goods or services from persons aged under 16 years.As a parent or guardian we encourage you to be aware of the activities in which your children are participating, both offline and online. If your children voluntarily disclose information, this may encourage unsolicited messages. We suggest that you discourage your child from providing any information without your consent.Sharing your information•	We only disclose information to third parties or individuals when obliged to by law.• Requests from an enforcement body (Including but not limited to Local Authorities, AHVLA, Police, VOSA, Official Veterinarians, DARD   Veterinary Service Enforcement Branch, the courts and the Food Standards Agency/FSA)•	If you have agreed that we may do so.•	When we use other companies to provide services on our behalf, e.g. processing, mailing or delivering orders, answering customers’ questions   about products or services, sending mail and emails or processing credit/debit card payments.•	If we receive a complaint about any content you have posted or transmitted to or from our website, to enforce or apply our Terms & Conditions   or if we believe that we need to do so to protect and defend the rights, property or personal safety of the British Appaloosa Society, our website or   our visitors and for other lawful purposes.•	And, we will never sell your personal information to any other organisation.
We do work with trusted companies under written policy agreements   which is in line with current General Data Protection Regulations, to process debit or Credit card payments (for example Paypal and PayaCard   Services) Those companies only process your data for the purpose we have instructed them to do so to fulfil a contract and then the information   is no longer retained and is securely deleted.Anything else?All of the personal data we process is processed by our Society officers in the UK, all of which have participated in training to make sure that they treat personal information with respect and due care, in line with our Policies and current GDPR LegislationIf you would like to change the way you hear from us or no longer wish to receive other communications from us then use the contact form on our website or email, telephone or write to our D.P.O (details at the end of this document)Retaining your informationWe hold your information only for as long as necessary for each purpose we use it•	Membership – Held for the duration of your membership and then for 6 years if you cease to be a member (unless you specifically request to be removed)
After a 6 year lapse, all of your personal information will be permanently removed from our records. Your information is securely archived but retained for this length of time because club membership is a paid transaction which forms part of our audited accounts. We are obligated to securely retain our accounts by Law•	Passport Issuing Organisation - Equine Passports and Updates – Are retained indefinitely to comply with UK/EU Equine Passport Legislation•	Financial information (ie debit/credit card details, paypal email addresses) are held to fulfil a contract and then deleted securely on conclusion.
We do not retain any financial information beyond this timescaleAbout the General Data Protection Regulations – MAY 2018A new data protection regulation (G.D.P.R) comes in force from May 2018 and gives everyone a number of very important rights. These are:•	Transparency over how we use your personal information (right to be informed).•	To request a copy of the information we hold about you, which will be provided to you within one month (right of access).•	To update or amend the information we hold about you if it is wrong (right of rectification).•	To ask us to stop using your information (in certain circumstances) (right to restrict processing).•	To ask us to remove your personal information from our records (right to be 'forgotten').•	To object to the processing of your information for marketing purposes (right to object).•	To obtain and reuse your personal data for your own purposes (right to data portability).•	To not be subject to a decision when it is based on automated processing (automated decision making and profiling).If you would like to know more about your rights under the data protection law please see the Information Commissioners Office websitehttps://ico.org.uk/Remember, you can change the way you hear from us or withdraw your permission for us to processing your personal data (except that obtained by Legal obligation) at any time by using the form on our Contact page or by the following:How to contact usIf you wish to talk through anything in our privacy policy, find out more about your rights or obtain a copy of the information we hold about you, please contact our Data Protection Officer (details at the bottom of this page) who will be happy to help. If you wish to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal data, you can contact our data protection officer who will investigate the matter. If you are not satisfied with our response or believe we are not processing your personal data in accordance with the law you can complain to The Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO).Our data protection officer can be contacted by writing to:Mrs Penny Oliver (BApS D.P.O)10 Roman WayWantageOxonOX12 9YFOr by emailing: secretary@appaloosa.org.ukIf you wish to talk to us about anything in this policy or the information we hold about you please contact our Chair/Registrar: Mrs Paula Moore: Tel; 07539 352 843Privacy Policy Last Updated: 18th May 2018
Copyright British Appaloosa Society © All rights Reserved.Privacy Policy plus T&CsCookies & Web PolicyGood Conduct Policy
Call us:
+44 7539 352 843
The 'British Appaloosa Society' is a charity and  private  non-profit making company limited by guarantee.        Registered No: 4836875     Registered Charity No: 1103432
Share by:
